* World

* World
* Podcasts

Breitbart Privacy Policy
========================

Last updated on September 27, 2024

Effective Date: January 10, 2020

This privacy policy (the “**Privacy Policy**”) discloses the privacy practices of Breitbart NEWS NETWORK, LLC (“**Breitbart**,” “**we**,” or “**us**”) including those on the breitbart.com website, all mobile websites and applications associated therewith (the “**Site**”) as well as when you contact us by phone, email, or otherwise. This Privacy Policy was developed to help you understand what information we collect as well as how we use and safeguard the information you provide to us on our Site.

**Information We Collect**

Personal Information You Provide To Us Or Ask A Third Party To Provide Us

* We may collect personal information, including your name, cell phone number, email address, financial information, physical address, and certain demographic data, when you choose to voluntarily provide to us such information, such as by subscribing to a newsletter or our subscription-based news and content service, ““Breitbart Fight Club”, making inquiries regarding our services, requesting breaking news alerts, reporting any problems with our Site, participating in a promotional offer, providing us with feedback on our Site, or otherwise.
* We may offer you various opportunities to engage in public activities and comment on articles on the Site. “Public activities” are any actions you take on the Site that are designed to be visible to other users, including comments, reviews, ratings or any other items that you submit. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other users of these areas. In addition to our privacy policy, please see Disqus’ privacy policy: [https://disqus.com/privacy-policy/](https://disqus.com/privacy-policy/) for more information on how your data is handled when you comment on articles.
* You may choose to associate your social media account with our Site (_e.g.,_ through Disqus, Facebook, Twitter or Google). By associating your accounts, you may be giving these third parties permission to send us certain information from your social media profile. What information they send us depends on your privacy settings with those third parties and their respective privacy policies. Once the accounts are associated, they may send us additional information from your profile over time. We will use the information they share with us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
* We also collect personal information from individuals who work for business contacts of Breitbart, such as service providers, vendors, and others.
* If you apply for a job posting, or become an employee, we collect information necessary to process your application or to retain you as an employee. This may include, among other things, your Social Security Number. Providing this information is required for employment.

Information Collected Using Technology

* We may collect and track information provided to us by your device, including the website you came from, browser type, unique device identifiers, IP address, domain name, geolocation information, time and date of access and other information. We may use this information alone or together with other personal information to individually customize the Site’s offerings and presentations.
* We may collect information about you through cookies, pixel tags, web beacons and similar technologies. Cookies are small strings of text sent by the Site to your browser which are then stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive.
* Our advertisers and other third parties may also use cookies to collect information about you, including when you click through the advertisement to their website.
* Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but it is possible to change your browser setup to allow you to control whether you will accept cookies, reject cookies, or to notify you each time a cookie is sent to you. If your browser is set to reject cookies, you may not be able to use or access all or a portion of our Site or features or may not receive personalization on the Site. In addition, advertisers may not recognize you when you return to their site. You may opt-out of online tracking based targeted advertising (e.g., cookies) by clicking the cookie settings link [here](https://www.breitbart.com/), or by scrolling to the bottom of the webpage and clicking on “Cookie Settings.”
* We also collect information from your mobile device such as unique identifying information broadcast from your device when visiting our website or using our mobile app.

**How We Use Your Information**

* We collect, retain and internally use information you provide us for various purposes, including, without limitation, to: correspond with you regarding our Site or services; inform you of developments in our company or with our services that we believe may be of interest to you; customize your use of the Site’s services; send you breaking news alerts; monitor Site traffic patterns and Site usage; comply with applicable laws; enforce our [Terms of Use](https://www.breitbart.com/terms-of-use/) or other agreements; maintain or administer the services, perform business analyses or for other internal purposes to improve the quality of our business, the Site and other products and services we offer; fulfill your subscription; and protect the rights, property or safety of the Site, our users and others.
* We may use information such as identifiers, demographic data, and preferences to allow advertising on the Site to be targeted to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users may see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and many advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer’s experience and the effectiveness of the advertising.
* We may use your information to show you relevant ads both on our services and elsewhere and measure the effectiveness and reach of ads.
* We may share your information for other purposes or to other parties with your consent.
* We may use the information collected from your mobile device to understand how you interact with us on your mobile device, save mobile application preferences such as notification settings and format, and serve you relevant advertisements while using the mobile application.

**When We May Disclose Your Information**

* We may provide your information, including your personal information to our service providers. Among other things, service providers may help us to administer our website, deliver subscriptions, conduct surveys, provide technical support, process payments, and assist in the fulfillment of orders.
* We may provide your information, including your personal information, to third parties, such as contractors and advertisers for a variety of purposes, including, without limitation, for direct marketing purposes.
* We may share in aggregate, statistical from non-personal information regarding the visitors to our Site, traffic patterns and Site usage with our partners, affiliates, investors, advertisers or other third parties.
* We may disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law or may disclose such information in response to a request from a law enforcement agency or authority, subpoena, court order or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
* We may share information with third parties in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the [Terms of Use](https://www.breitbart.com/terms-of-use/) or as otherwise required by law.
* In the future, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, we may include your information among the transferred assets.
* We may share your information with third party advertising companies to target and serve some of the advertisements that appear on our Site and elsewhere, and these companies likewise may use their own cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to collect information from users of our Site. These companies may use that information, sometimes in conjunction with similar information gathered from other websites, to deliver advertisements on this Site or elsewhere, tailored to match the interests of consumers.
* We may disclose your information to other third parties when we have your consent or direction to do so.

The table below describes the categories of personal information we collect, disclose for a business purpose and “share.” Please note, in addition to the recipients identified below, we may disclose any of the categories of personal information we collect with government entities, as may be needed to comply with law or prevent illegal activity. We do not “sell” your personal information for money or other valuable consideration. As discussed elsewhere in the Privacy Policy, we use cookies and similar tracking technologies for purposes of targeted advertising.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Category of Personal Information | Disclosures for a Business Purpose | Sharing for Cross-Context Behavioral Advertising |
| Identifiers – this may include real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, email address, account name, or other similar identifiers. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Joint marketing partners<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Payment processors and financial institutions<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms<br>* Social networks | * Advertising networks |
| Demographic Data | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms<br>* Social networks | * Advertising Networks |
| Government Issued Identification – this may include social security number, driver’s license number, or state issued identification number, passport number. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms | * N/A |
| Financial Information – this may include bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, and other financial information. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms<br>* Payment processors and financial institutions | * N/A |
| Characteristics of protected classifications – this may include age, sex, race, ethnicity, physical, or mental handicap, etc. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms | * N/A |
| Commercial information – this may include information about products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Joint marketing partners<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firms<br>* Social networks | * Advertising networks |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information – this may include browsing history, search history, and information regarding an individual’s interaction with an internet website, application, or advertisement. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Joint marketing partners<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Payment processors and financial institutions<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firm<br>* Social networks | * Advertising networks |
| Professional or employment-related information | * Affiliates or subsidiaries | * N/A |
| Non-public education information (as defined in the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act) | * Affiliates or subsidiaries | * N/A |
| Inferences drawn from any of the information listed above | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Joint marketing partners<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Payment processors and financial institutions<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firm<br>* Social networks | * N/A |
| Additional categories of personal information described in theCaliforniaCustomer Records statute (Cal.Civ.Code§1798.80(e)) – this may include signature, physical characteristics, or description, insurance policy number. | * Affiliates or subsidiaries<br>* Business partners<br>* Data analytics providers<br>* Internet service providers<br>* Joint marketing partners<br>* Operating systems and platforms<br>* Other Service Providers<br>* Payment processors and financial institutions<br>* Professional services organizations, this may include auditors and law firm<br>* Social networks | * N/A |

**Links to Third Party Websites**

Our Site may offer links to other websites, including links embedded in advertisements and links to various news sources that are not under the control of Breitbart. Such links to other websites may have information policies and practices different from ours. In addition, certain companies associated with the Site may have their own privacy policies. We do not own or control such companies and websites and are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices or the content of websites that we do not own or control.

**How We Protect and Retain Your Information**

We use reasonable industry-accepted technology and controls to protect your data from disclosure to unauthorized third parties. Although these measures are typically effective, use of the Internet and related computer systems is inherently vulnerable to unauthorized access or “hacking.” No guarantee can be given that all information you provide to us will not be accessed by unauthorized persons. Thus, please note that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. In the event that we are required by law to inform you of a breach to your personal information we may notify you electronically, in writing, or by telephone, if permitted to do so by law.

We retain your personal information for only as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of the information, the purposes for which we obtained the information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, as well as applicable legal requirements.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. Unless we obtain your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

**Accessibility**

You may be able to enable accessibility features on our Site to make this Privacy Policy more accessible to you. You may also contact us using the information below to request an alternate format of this Privacy Policy.

**Notice to California Residents**

1. Marketing

California law permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we have disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared such information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request to [privacy@breitbart.com](mailto:privacy@breitbart.com).

1. Sensitive Information Disclosure

We collect the following categories of sensitive personal information (as defined under California law): an employee’s social security number, driver’s license, state identification card or passport number, an employee’s account log-in, financial account, password, or credentials allowing access to an account. This information is collected in order to process transactions, comply with laws, manage our business, or provide you with services. Note that we do not use such information for any purposes that are not identified within the California Privacy Rights Act Section 1798.121. We do not “sell” or “share” sensitive personal information for purposes of cross-context behavioral advertising.

**Your Choices**

Some jurisdictions give you a right to make the following choices regarding your personal information. Note that your rights may vary depending on your jurisdiction.

* **Access To Your Personal Information.** You may request access to your personal information or confirmation that we have information about you. In certain limited circumstances, you may also request to receive access to your data in a portable, machine-readable format.
* **Changes To Your Personal Information.** We rely on you to update and correct your personal information. If our website does not permit you to update or correct certain information, you can contact us at the address described below in order to request that your information by modified. You may ask us to correct information that is inaccurate or incomplete. Note that we may keep historical information in our backup files as permitted by law.
* **Deletion Of Your Personal Information.** You may request that we delete your personal information. If required by law, we will grant a request to delete information, but you should note that in many situations we must keep your personal information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, or for another business purposes.
* **Opt-out of Targeted Advertising.** You may opt-out of online tracking based targeted advertising (e.g., cookies) by clicking the cookie settings link [here](https://www.breitbart.com/), or by scrolling to the bottom of the webpage and clicking on “Cookies Settings.” Please note that if you change browsers or computers, or if you clear your browser’s cache, you may need to click the link again to apply your preference. We also recognize [Global Privacy Control (GPC) signals](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) enabled by customers on their web browser or web browser extension as valid opt-out requests where required by applicable law. Please note that your opt-out preference signal will be applied only to your current browser and device. For more information about GPC, please visit [Global Privacy Control](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/).
* **Objection to Certain Processing.** You may object to our use or disclosure of your personal information by contacting us at the address described below.
* **Online Tracking.** We do not currently recognize the “Do Not Track” signal. This law also requires website and app operators to disclose whether third parties may collect personally identifiable information about their users’ online activities over time and across different websites and apps when the users use the operator’s website or app. We may permit third parties to collect personally identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across different web sites and apps when a consumer uses our Site.
* **Promotional Emails.** We may send promotional materials to you, as well as targeted offers from third parties. If, at any time, you prefer not to receive email marketing information or newsletters from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email.
* **Revocation Of Consent.** Where we process your personal information based upon consent, you may revoke consent. Please note, if you revoke your consent for the processing of personal information then we may no longer be able to provide you services.

Please note, not all of the rights described above are absolute, and they do not apply in all circumstances. In some cases, we may limit or deny your request because the law permits or requires us to do so, or if we are unable to adequately verify your identity. We will not discriminate against individuals who exercise their privacy rights under applicable law.

**Submitting Requests**

You may exercise the rights described above through our [online portal](https://www.breitbart.com/contact-us/dsr-form/). If you disagree with how we handled a request, you may appeal our decision by contacting us with the subject line “Appeal.”

Note that, as required by law, we will require you to prove your identity. We may verify your identity by phone call or email. Depending on your request, we will ask for information such as your name, email address, or phone number. We may also ask you to provide a signed declaration confirming your identity.

Designated Agent

In some circumstances, you may designate an authorized agent to submit requests to exercise certain privacy rights on your behalf. We will require verification that you provided the authorized agent permission to make a request on your behalf. You must provide us with a copy of the signed permission you have given to the authorized agent to submit the request on your behalf and verify your own identity directly with us. If you are an authorized agent submitting a request on behalf of an individual, you must attach authorization to act on the consumer’s behalf to the request. If we do not receive this information, the request will be denied.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@breitbart.com](mailto:privacy@breitbart.com) or send a written request to Breitbart News Network, c/o Webmaster, 149 S. Barrington Ave., #735, Los Angeles, CA 90049.

Copyright © 2024 Breitbart
